# Joshua Ogunyinka

# Joshua Ogunyinka

BM 17, Jaybee house, Orita-Iloko, Ilesha Osun state, Nigeria

+234-703-350-0593

ogunyinkajoshua@yahoo.com linkedin.com/in/iamogunyinka github.com/iamOgunyinka

**Skills** 

Solid knowledge of modern C++

Solid knowledge of Window API and it's internals

Good knowledge of frameworks: POCO, Boost (Signals, Serializer), Qt

Good knowledge of designing and writing multithreaded systems

Good knowledge of Design Patterns and OOP best practices

Good knowledge of VCS and CI: Git and SVN

Knowledge of SQLite, MySql and PostgreSQL

Knowledge of unit testing: Google Tests, TDD

Knowledge of integration with Web APIs: JSON, XML

Knowledge of Scrum methodology

**Key Skills** 

Languages: C, C++, Python.

Frameworks/Libraries: Qt, Boost, CppRestSdk, Flask, Django

**Build Systems:** GNU Make, QMake

Operating System: Windows, Ubuntu Linux, FreeBSD

**Shell Scripting:** Bash (Linux)

Web: HTML, XHTML, XML, JSON SQL DBMSs: MySQL, PostgreSQL

Web Servers: Nginx

**Profiling Tools**: Valgrind Suite, KCacheGrind, prof, gprof, etc.

**Load Testing Tools**: JMeter

IDEs: Visual Studio, PyCharm, QtCreator

# **Projects**

# FastSub(Private repository, Present)

FastSub is a network security tool for penetration testers that allows them to query DNS servers for names, record types and find available services available on that domain using user-supplied resolver IPs.

# **Interlace**(PC, Present)

Interlace is a network security tool that easily turn single threaded command line applications into a fast, multi-threaded application with CIDR and glob support.

# Tragel (Android, PC, Web Server. May 2019 - Present)

A software platform that revolutionize how society buys and sells. It is implemented with the concept of company and customers, although the company could be any small, medium scale enterprise or an international conglomerate.

#### fs::cpp(2014 - 2019)

An implementation of the standard file system proposal for the C++ language for non-C++17 compilers running on Windows.

## Tuq(Android, PC, Web Server. Aug 2017 - Dec 2017)

An android app, powered by a Python server, that makes multiple-choice question tests more meaningful and modern for institutions of higher learning. It is designed to be standalone platform-independent. It has no MCQ tests embedded in itself but depends solely on the general public to set questions and their respective answers. It is revolutionary.

## Mary-Lang(Mar 2016 - Dec 2017)

Mary-Lang is a gradual typed programming language that borrows dynamism from Python and JS, syntax from C# and C++ with a whole lot of functionality from other popular programming languages

# **Experience**

#### IT Manager( April 2018 - Nov. 2018 )

Heringan Hotel and Suites

Development of desktop and server software

Development and maintenance of company's website

#### Software and Web Developer (September 2017- March 2018)

Independent Software Developer

Design and implementation of Software for private clients

# Software Engineer (January 2016 - August 2017)

Froist Inc, Osun state, Nigeria

Development of technical libraries of a desktop and server software.

Porting and maintaining existing software across different platforms.

# Junior Software Engineer (May 2014 - November 2015)

TigerScope Solutions, Kwara state, Nigeria

Contributed to the development of hospitality management payment system. I also got the opportunity to learn a lot by developing diversified backend, embedded, desktop and web projects as well as put my existing experience to exercise for further grooming.

# **Education**

## **UNIVERSITY OF ILORIN / PostGraduate Diploma**

November 2016 - October 2017 / Ilorin, Nigeria

PostGraduate Diploma in Computer Science(Distinction)

#### FEDERAL POLYTECHNIC OFFA/ Higher National Diploma

November 2011 - May 2014 / Offa, Nigeria

Higher National Diploma(HND) in Computer Science(Upper Credit)

# THE POLYTECHNIC ILE-IFE/ Ordinary National Diploma

November 2007 - March 2009 / Ile-Ife, Nigeria

Ordinary National Diploma(HND) in Computer Science(Lower Credit)

#### About

I am an experienced modern backend programmer with hands-on experience in C++ and Python for planning, designing, implementing, and testing enterprise level products. With C++/Qt(with Python running on the server), I have built reliable systems that are used by some hospitality management systems in Nigeria.